Finding Aid for Raymond H. Kahn papers, 1968-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Raymond H. Kahn papers 1968-1982
Kahn, Raymond H., 1930-
1 linear foot
861134 Aa 2
Physician and professor of anatomy at the University of Michigan. Files relate to police-student relations, 1968-1973, to the review of the Division of Research Development and Administration, 1980, and to research policy and Department of Defense sponsored research at the University.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Professor Kahn (donor no. 6831 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Raymond H. Kahn earned his bachelor's and master's degrees in zoology at the University of California. He was awarded a Ph.D. in zoology from the University of California, Berkeley, in 1953, then joined the University of Michigan Medical School faculty in 1954 as instructor of anatomy. He became assistant professor in 1958, associate professor in 1962 and was promoted to professor in 1967. He retired from the University in1982, after which he became assistant director of research for the Research Institute of Scripps Clinic in La Jolla.
At the University of Michigan, Kahn was elected to the Medical School Executive Committee and to the University's Senate Assembly. He also helped initiate the School's Integrated Medical-Premedical Program, or Inteflex. In addition, Kahn received national and international recognition for his research in tissue and organ culture. He conducted pioneering studies on the development of endothelial linings for vascular prostheses.
Raymond H. Kahn died July 5, 1996 in La Jolla, Calif.
The Kahn papers consists of a single Topical file relating primarily to Kahn's participation in various University of Michigan reviews, surveys, committees, and task forces. Much of the collection concerns police-student relations at the University and Kahn's participation in a review of the Division of Research Development and Administration in 1980.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Division of Research Development and Administration.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan--Research.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1971-1980.
- Topical file
  - Alumnae Athena Awards, 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Biomedical Research Council, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Police Student Relations, 1968-1973
    - Campus Disorder Planning (J.F. Brinkerhoff), 1971 (Box 1)
    - Security Operations: Survey of University of Michigan Security Operations (Berg and Berg Associates), 1969 (Box 1)
    - University Council
      - Emergency Guidelines, 1971 (Box 1)
      - A Survey of Police and Security Needs of the University of Michigan at Ann Arbor, 1973, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - University Police Relations Committee, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Review of the Division of Research Development and Administration, 1980
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Report and Notes (Box 1)
    - Minutes of Ad Hoc DRDA Review Committee (Box 1)
    - Documents, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Senate Assembly
    - Advisory Committee on Academic Affairs, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Department of Defense Sponsored Research at the University of Michigan (Box 1)
    - Indirect Costs (Box 1)
    - Research Policies Committee
      - 1975-1981 (Box 1)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Vice-President for Research
    - Governor's Molecular Biology Task Force, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Incentives for Research at the University of Michigan, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Report on the Volume of Research to the Regents, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - Task Force on University/Industry Interaction -- Michigan Research Council, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 1)